ANWANA JOHN

DESCRIPTION

A motivated and driven Software developer with an eye for detail and a knack for problem-solving. Adept in Web development using Django Web Framework or Express JS/Nest JS for Back-End development, Front-End development with Javascript (React and jQuery) and Html5/CSS (Bootstrap), and stand-alone APIs with Django Rest Framework/Express JS/Nest JS.

Also experienced in Unit Testing, error debugging, web hosting management, payment gateway integration, and search engine optimization. Very adaptable to new software development technologies with quick uptake times and the ability to deliver on schedule.

SKILLS

Adept with Python, Javascript and TypeScript programming languages.

Experienced with the NodeJS, Express, Django, DRF, React and jQuery frameworks and libraries.

Experienced utilizing VCS (Git).

Unit Testing and Error Debugging.

Database Management with SQL and PostgreSQL.

Progressive Web App Development.

Data Analysis with Pandas.

Proficient with MS Office suite.

Excellent communication skills (8.0 avg. Band score on IELTS.)

Good team player with Personnel relationship building skills.

EXPERIENCE

QUOMODO SYSTEMS LIMITED, Remote - FullStack Developer

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Functional Requirements Document development
- Design prototype conversion using the ReactJS library.
- API development with ASP.NET Core framework in C#.
- API consumption using Redux.

MUVE MONEY, Remote - API development for e-wallet

NOVEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

- API creation and development using the Django Rest Framework
- Model development for Database creation to handle User, Admin, Agent and Account records.
- Integrate User Authentication with Java Web Token.
- Develop API endpoints to handle Request and POST data.
- Integrate Paystack payment systems.
- Integrate GIS to make API location-aware.

HNG Internship, Remote - Machine Learning intern

SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

- Data analysis and information extraction.
- Developing recommender systems with machine learning.
- Developed an image classification system.
- Developed an AI text summarizer.
- Web scraping using Selenium and Python Requests Library

Ministry of Water Resources, Enugu - N.Y.S.C. Placement

November 2016 - October 2017

- Files and inventory management
- Drainage system management.

Hamilton Nigeria Ltd., Port Harcourt - intern

August 2013 - January 2014

- Drilling mud preparation and analysis.
- Mud properties analysis.

Schlumberger Nigeria Ltd., Port Harcourt - intern

August 2012 - January 2013

- MWD tools servicing.
- Rig up and Rig down.
- New Employee Safety Training

EDUCATION

Rivers State University, Port Harcourt — Bachelor of Technology

August 2008 - August 2014, RIVERS STATE

Completed a degree in Petroleum Engineering and graduated with 3.27 CGPA.

Nigerian Navy Secondary School, Port Harcourt - W.A.S.S.C.E

September 2001 - July 2007, RIVERS STATE

GITHUB

https://github.com/jayanwana/

REFEREES

Would be provided on request.